https://ipi.media/privacy-policy/

Cyprus
Cyprus (North)
Impressum
Responsible for the content of this website as well as for the IPI Newsletter is:
International Press Institute (IPI)
Chair of the IPI Executive Board: Markus Spillmann
The full of list of members of the IPI Executive Board is available here.
The International Press Institute (IPI) is a global network of editors, media executives and leading journalists. We are dedicated to the furtherance and safeguarding of press freedom, protecting freedom of opinion and expression, promoting the free flow of news and information, and improving the practices of journalism.
Read more about us here.
IPI is an international non-governmental organisation as defined in the Austrian Federal Act on the Granting of Privileges to Non-Governmental International Organizations (Federal Law Gazette No. 174/1992).
Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy explains how and why we may collect your personal data when you visit or use our website, including our e-mail newsletter.
IPI strongly values the privacy of its members and visitors and makes every effort to protect any data provided to us. We update this Privacy Policy from time to time and encourage visitors review the Policy on a regular basis.
Please note that this Policy governs information collected through https://ipi.media/and any subpages. It does not apply to ontheline.media, an anonymous, encrypted communications platform for which special security measures exist.
What personal information do we collect on or through our website?
If you are just visiting our website, we do not collect any personal information from you.
We may ask you to provide certain personal data when you contact us through our website, fill out any forms on our website or when you take advantage of certain services we offer, such as when you sign up for our electronic newsletter. These data enable us to effectively communicate with you and provide you with personalised content.
We currently use external providers, Wirecard and PayPal, to process web-based payments to IPI, including donations and membership fees. By using Wirecard and PayPal, you consent to its terms of service, including as they relate to privacy. For its part, IPI does not store your credit card number or billing information electronically.
Cookies
Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enable the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognise your browser and remember certain information.
We use cookies in order to learn about how visitors interact with our website so as to better understand our audience and to continually improve users’ experience of our website. Cookies provide us with statistics on web traffic to the site and how visitors navigate through the site once there. Such data is always collected in an anonymous and aggregate fashion using third-party services such as Google Analytics. Your personal data is not recorded in such cases.
You can block cookies by changing the preferences in your web browser. Please note that disabling cookies may prevent you from fully accessing some of the site’s features.
Storing your data
Personal data that we collect from you is stored primarily on our secure servers located in Austria. However, in some cases your data may be stored on servers located outside of Austria if they have been shared with IPI representative bodies in other countries; or when they have been shared with third parties in other countries following your consent. By sharing your data with us, you agree to this data transfer, storage or processing.
We take the security of your data very seriously and make every effort to ensure the integrity thereof. Nevertheless, despite precautions, the provision and storage of electronic data can not be considered completely secure. Therefore, sharing your data with us is entirely at your own risk.
Sharing your data
We will not disclose your personal data to any parties outside of IPI’s organisational structure without your consent. An exception applies in cases required by law or if we believe there has been an inappropriate intereference with our website or services.
Aggregate statistical information on web traffic may on occasion be shared with organisation stakeholders, such as donors, or with third-party service providers, such as website managers or designers.
IPI newsletter
We encourage those interested in our work to sign up for our weekly newsletter. Those on our newsletter mailing list may occasionally receive additional communications on specific topics or events that we believe may be of interest.
The subscription process has been updated to comply with the new General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) that came into effect on May 25, 2018.
You may unsubscribe from our newsletter at any time through a link included in each newsletter e-mail. If you experience any difficulties in unsubscribing, please contact us directly at info[at]ipi.media.
Liability
IPI regularly checks and modifies information on its website, but published information may at times no longer be valid. IPI accepts no liability for the correctness or completeness of the information and data provided on its website, and information published on IPI’s website is not to be considered legal advice.
IPI accepts no liability for any direct or indirect damages that may arise from the use of any information or data content on its website, nor shall it accept liability for any damages arising as a consequence of accessing any other websites via links provided on the site. IPI does not guarantee that information, software or other material that is accessible via its website is free of viruses or any other damaging components.
Third-party websites
Our website may include links to various third parties, including partner organisations, advertisers, donors or external service providers. IPI does not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy policies or standards of any third-party websites. Similarly, we are not responsible for the availability or content or these external sites, nor do we endorse, guarantee or warrant the information, services or products available on these sites.
Copyright
The text of this website is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution Licence. Except where expressly indicated otherwise, you are welcome to use and share the text of this website provided you attribute the International Press Institute (IPI) as the source. All photos are copyright of their respective source.
Contact us
For any questions related to this Policy or to the use of your data, please contact us directly at info[at]ipi.media.
Jurisdiction
Any legal matters arising from the use of IPI’s website are to be governed by Austrian law, with Vienna as the place of jurisdiction.
